海盗派斯倾情奉献
大家好
Ahoy
这里是海绵宝宝特辑
It's a SpongeBob SquarePants Special
海绵宝宝特辑
准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
小蜗不见了
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
编剧
客串嘉宾
插曲演唱
制片指导
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
派大星
Hey, Patrick
你这是在干什么
What are you doing?
给小蜗搬这一大袋的蜗牛粮
Carrying this heavy bag of snail food for Gary
小蜗最近怎样
How is Gary?
好得很
He's fine
派大星  能不能待会再聊
Pat, can we talk about this some other time?
蜗牛粮真的太重了
This snail food is really heavy
行吧
Sure
不过我有事要跟你说
But there was something I wanted to tell you
很重要的事
Something important
想起来了
I remember
我刚是在跟谁讲话
Who was I talking to?
快看这是个什么东西
Ahoy, Captain, what have we here?
是封小小的格式信
It's a tiny form letter
亲爱的先生或者女士
Dear Sir or Ma'am
很抱歉我们错过您了
We are sorry we missed you
我们会尽快再次为您寄送包裹
We will attempt to re-deliver your package
at our earliest convenience
谁啊
Hello?
我的包裹
My package
看下收到什么了
Let's see what we got here
美人鱼战士与企鹅男孩
美人鱼战士与企鹅男孩官方球拍组
My official Mermaid Man and Barnacle Boy
paddleball set
官方球拍组
尼克公司
这什么东西
What's this?
快接受肮脏泡泡的挑战
Take the Dirty Bubble Challenge
连续拍球
Hit the paddleball
29998559671349下不中断
29,998,559,671,349 times in a row
肮脏泡泡  无论你漂浮在何处
Dirty Bubble, wherever you float
我特此接受你的挑战
I hereby accept your challenge
真是的
Darn it
小蜗
真是的
Darn it
什么声音
What was that?
小蜗  原来害我分心的声音是你发的
Gary, that distracting sound came from you
对不起  我没办法跟你一起玩
I'm sorry, I can't play with you right now
美人鱼战士需要我
Mermaid Man needs me
小蜗  我可求你了
Gary, please
我正努力打败肮脏泡泡呢
I'm trying to defeat the Dirty Bubble
先让我弄清楚  小蜗
So, let's get this straight, Gary
你不想要我打败肮脏泡泡是吧
You don't want me to defeat the Dirty Bubble
要知道肮脏泡泡可是
You know, Dirty Bubble
七大洋里的恐怖分子
terror of the seven seas
专门对付我最爱的电视超级英雄
arch nemesis of my favorite TV superheroes
美人鱼战士和企鹅男孩
Mermaid Man and Barnacle Boy
很明显还是
and apparently
知名的拍球冠军
renowned paddleball champion
球拍组
至少我认识到了这个任务有多重要
Well, I for one, recognize the importance
of this undertaking
但你有没有认识到  我就不清楚了
But whether or not you do remains to be seen
如果你不介意的话  我要继续挑战了
Now, if you don't mind, I would like to get back to it
宠物啊
Pets
有时候真不知道它们听不听得懂人话
Sometimes, I wonder if
they understand a word you're saying
小蜗  我不喜欢你这样子
Gary, I hate it when you do that
快滚
Now get
让你的主人完成这项重要的挑战
And leave your master to his important affairs
真是的
Darn it
拍一个了
I got one
肮脏泡泡  去死吧你
Dirty Bubble, say your prayers
离开
蜗牛快车
已经好几天没见到海绵宝宝了
I haven't seen SpongeBob in a couple days
他等下一定会很高兴能知道
I'm sure he'll be glad to know
我记起来要跟他说什么了
I remember what I wanted to tell him
好奇怪
That's strange
平常我都用这只手敲门的
Usually, I knock on the with this hand
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
你在吗
You around?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
真是的
Darn it
海绵宝宝  是你吗
SpongeBob, is that you?
真是的
Darn it
海绵宝宝的厨房
真是的
Darn it
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
真是的
Darn it
海绵宝宝  怎么回事
SpongeBob, what happened?
这幅画给挂歪了
This picture is crooked
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
真是的
Darn it
振作起来
Snap out of it
派大星  我
Patrick, I
怎么了  兄弟
What is it, buddy?
跟我说
You can tell me
我接受了肮脏泡泡的挑战
I took the Dirty Bubble challenge
什么
You what?
你怎么哭了  派大星
Why are you crying, Patrick?
我哭是因为
Because
好多年以前
many years ago
我接受了那场挑战
I took that challenge
真的吗
Really?
后来怎样了
What happened?
我赢了
I won
不过发过来的奖杯让我给丢了
But then I lost the trophy they sent me
你丢了
You lost the
太可怕了
That's terrible
没事的  派大星
Come on, Pat
来吃点海草饼干配海马奶喝
Let's have some kelp cookies and seahorse milk
我每次丢东西都会那样解闷
that always cheers me up when I've lost something
给你  派大星
There you are, Pat
新鲜海马奶
Fresh seahorse milk
谢谢兄弟
Thanks, buddy
派大星
Hey, Pat
有没有一种好像忘记了什么的感觉
You ever feel like you're forgetting something?
很重要的东西
Something important?
应该跟这个食盆有点关系
I think it has something to do with this bowl
小蜗的食盆
Gary's food bowl
小蜗
对了
That's it
我得喂小蜗
I gotta feed Gary
才放几个小时  灰尘就积这么多
That's a lot of dust for a couple of hours
小蜗
Gary
吃饭了
Dinner
小蜗快来吃
Come on, Gary
开饭了
Soup's on
小蜗
Gary?
派大星
Hey, Pat?
什么事
Yeah?
我接受肮脏泡泡的挑战有多长时间了
How long was I taking the Dirty Bubble challenge?
大概一周了
About a week
一周了
A week?
真这么久吗
Are you sure?
那个
Well
对  大概一周
Yeah, it's about a week
也可能十天了
maybe ten days
十天了
Ten days?
小蜗
Gary
派大星
Patrick
我找不到小蜗了
I can't find Gary
这办法肯定行
This never fails
小蜗最爱的点心
Gary's favorite treats
保证可以吸引小蜗
Gary can't resist these babies
里面装满了八种有机成分
They're filled with eight types of organic sediment
小蜗这种底栖生物吃了还会想再吃
that bottom feeders like Gary can't get enough of
有八种
Eight?
对  差不多吧
Yeah, something like that
只要摇一摇罐子就行了
All you really have to do is shake the can
小蜗每次听到都会跑过来的
Gary comes running every time
摇吧  派大星
Go on, Pat
试试看
Try it
我来摇摇看
Let me see that
怎么会这样  这可是全新的
I don't understand, this is a brand-new
我只吃出来六种有机成分
I only tasted six types of sediment
小蜗
Gary
小蜗  你在哪
Gary, where are you?
你在这下面吗
Are you under here?
小蜗
Gary
继续摇  派大星
Keep shaking, Patrick
小蜗
Gary
那两个野蛮人又在干什么
What are those Neanderthals up to?
不知道我忙着在享受吗
Don't they know I'm busy spoiling myself?
你去那边找
You check over there
我在这里面找
I'll check in here
找到了吗  派大星
Find him yet, Pat?
没找到  我会继续找的
No, but I'll keep looking
可是已经没别的地方可以找了
But there's nowhere left to look
There's one place we haven't checked
有一个地方还没有找过
小蜗应该塞不进去的
I doubt Gary could fit in there
咱看就看呗
Can't hurt to look
海绵宝宝
来碰个运气
Here goes nothing
派大星  你看
Look, Pat
什么东西
What is it?
看看写了啥
Let's see
亲爱的海绵宝宝
Dear SpongeBob
尽管过去几年是我一生最美好的时光
These last few years have been
some of the best of my life
但是我必须要远走了
but I must move on
不用麻烦你过来找我了
Don't bother to come looking for me
现在我可能已经找到了新主人
By now, I have probably found a new owner
能记得帮我装好食盆喂我
who actually remembers to fill up
my food bowl every now and again
小蜗谨上
Sincerely, Gary
至少这名字要用到新主人给我取名前
At least until my new owner renames me
海神王啊
Dear Neptune
我都干了些什么
What have I done?
你几个意思
What do you mean?
是你赶人家走的
You drove him away
这上边白纸黑字清清楚楚
It's right there in black and white
看见没
See?
就在这边
Right there
还有这边
and there
小蜗
Gary
最后一家
咖啡店
酒店
食物
睡
吃
我裤子穿太高了吗  亲爱的
Are my pants too high, dear?
玉米片
看看是谁来蹭饭了
Look who came to dinner
那位应该不喜欢玉米片
Guess he didn't like nachos
你在这啊
There you are
你在这啊  肥肥小妹
There you are, Miss Tuffsy
老奶奶可终于找见你了
Gramma finally found you
人家都开始担心起来了
She was starting to get worried
我们回家去吧  肥肥小妹
Now let's get to your home, Miss Tuffsy
给你吃点好的
and get you something to eat
你比老奶奶印象里的还要轻得多
You feel much lighter than Gramma remembers
好好坐  肥肥小妹
There you go, Miss Tuffsy
老奶奶知道你要电热毯毯舒服暖和
Gramma knows you like your Mr. Heaty set to extra cozy
来陪你在家放松
when you're home relaxing
天啊  你饼干就要吃光了
Goodness, you're almost out of cookies
我去再拿一点来
Here, I'll go and get some more
你不可以再偷跑出去了
Now, don't you go running off again
给你
There you go
吃完后
After this
先前说好要做的恶魔蛋会再去做的
I'll go make up some of those deviled eggs I promised
来点音乐怎么样
How about a little music?
老奶奶家的音响可厉害了
Gramma's got a killer stereo system
这首歌让老奶奶想起了做铆工的时光
This song reminds Gramma of her days as a riveter
你让老奶奶感觉年轻了不少
You make Gramma feel so young
来吧  肥肥小妹
Come on, Miss Tuffsy
来跳点布吉伍吉
Let's do the boogie-woogie
[ 布吉伍吉：一种音乐风格 ]
好了  布吉伍吉跳够了
Okay, that's enough of the boogie-woogie for now
裤头村
小蜗
Gary
帽子
小蜗
Gary
饥饿蜗牛
蜗牛粮
小蜗
Gary
老奶奶知道你有多爱
Gramma knows how much you love
这些深夜犯罪剧
these late-night crime drama programs
对不对  肥肥小妹
Don't you, Miss Tuffsy?
天啊  这么晩了
Heavens, look at the time
该睡觉了  肥肥小妹
It's time for bed, Miss Tuffsy
别吵  小蜗
Quiet, Gary
不知道我在忙吗
Can't you see I'm busy?
你房间到了  肥肥小妹
Here's your room, Miss Tuffsy
睡吧  亲爱的
Here you are, darling
老奶奶来给你盖被子
Let Gramma tuck you in
好了
There you go
差点忘了给你亲一下道晩安了
I almost forgot your good night kiss
祝你好梦  肥肥小妹
Sweet dreams, Miss Tuffsy
蟹堡王
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
你迟到了十五分钟
You're 15 minutes late
抱歉  蟹老板
Sorry, Mr. Krabs
我一整晩都在外头找小蜗
I was out all night looking for Gary
知道吗  小蜗离家出走了
You see, he ran away and
我就
Well, now I
海绵宝宝  你没事吧
SpongeBob, are you okay?
你看起来有点
You look kinda
不对劲
different
我说不上没事  蟹老板
Well, I'm not exactly what you'd call okay, Mr. Krabs
知道吗  我家
You see, my
你只是忘了戴帽子而已
You just forgot to put your hat on
就知道能解决
Knew I'd figure it out
小蜗
Gary
没错  我要退了这个蟹黄堡
Yeah, I'd like a refund for this Krabby Patty
退了
Refund?
里面有什么问题
What's wrong with it?
其实没什么
Nothing, really
只是上面全是眼泪
except that it's covered in tears
搞什么
What the
小蜗
Gary
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
小子  外面还有客人
There's customers out there, boy
等着要吃东西
waiting to be fed
这可不是我第一次
This wouldn't be the first time
让某个挨饿的失望了
I disappointed someone who was hungry
没事  小子
Okay, boy
要不你跟蟹老板说说出了什么事吧
Why don't you tell Mr. Krabs what's wrong
知道吗
Well, you see
说够了  小子
That's enough, boy
其实  重要的不总是你说的话
See, its not always what you say that matters
有时  是你没说出口的话
Sometimes, it's what you don't say
懂吗
Understand?
懂了  蟹老板
Yes, Mr. Krabs
我本该告诉小蜗在我心中有多重要
I should've told Gary how important he was to me
虽然不知道这事跟做蟹黄堡有何关系
Well, I don't know what that has to do with
making Krabby Patties
但是我很清楚一句话
but I do know this
任何问题
Any problem you have
只要努力工作  即可迎刃而解
can be solved with a little hard work
说得对  蟹老板
You're right, Mr. Krabs
这才像话
That's me boy
如果我要找到小蜗的话
If I'm going to find Gary
就要加倍努力去找才行
I'm going to need to work harder at it
世界末日到了
It's the apocalypse
办公用品从天上掉下来了
Office products falling from the sky
不是这样  派大星
No, Patrick
我们得用这些东西去找小蜗
We're going to use this stuff to go find Gary
明明就是你赶走小蜗的
But I thought you drove him away
还不把小蜗当一回事
with your neglect and indifference
派大星  现在不是说闲话的时候了
Patrick, now is not the time for talking
我们有任务在身
We've got work to do
给你喝  肥肥小妹
There you go, Miss Tuffsy
新鲜现挤的
Fresh squeezed
虽然用挤的会比较久
It takes longer to make it that way
不过这可都是我为爱做的
but it was a labor of love
煎饼上面再多撒点糖浆怎么样
How about a little more syrup on those pancakes?
火车过来了
Here comes the train
好好玩一场吧  肥肥小妹
Set phasers on fun, Miss Tuffsy
玛莎手工店
到了
Here we are
促销
仅限今日
这个地方好
Here's a good spot
小蜗
Gary
我很对不起
I am sorry
求你回家吧
Please come home
爱你的  海绵宝宝
Love, SpongeBob
赶紧的  胶带给我
Quick, hand me the tape
促销
仅限今日
店里在做香薰松果大促销
They're having a sale on scented pine cones
派大星  现在不是做这个的时候
Patrick, this is no time for that
松果
Pine cones
这种做手工用的绒条挺不错的
These pipe cleaners are simply delightful
老太太  你赶紧的
Old lady, quick
我在找香薰松果
I'm looking for the scented pine cones
这可是紧急情况
It's an emergency
希望你不是因为要买才来找的  孩子
Well, I hope you weren't looking to buy them, sonny
因为老奶奶已经全部都买走了
because Gramma already picked up all they had
你和我又要再一次分别了
Once again, you and I are kept apart
可爱的香薰松果啊
O sweet scented pine cones
小蜗
Hey, Gary
好了
There
快点  派大星
Come on, Pat
把传单拿了发出去
Just take these fliers and hand them out
快点  肥肥小妹
Come on, Miss Tuffsy
还有好多好玩的事情可以做
there's plenty more fun to be had
小蜗
我
爱
你
小蜗我知道
Gary, now I know
我错了
I was wrong
求你
回家
我搞砸了
I messed up
小蜗
你出走了
and now you're gone
美发                                                              美甲
Gary, I'm sorry I neglected you
小蜗我对不起忽视了你
我从来没有想过你会远走
Oh, I never expected you to run away
让我感到如此的空虚
and leave me feeling this empty
小蜗
求你回家吧
你的喵声现在对我而言好似天籁
Your meow right now would sound like music to me
求你回家
Please come home
因为我想你  小蜗
'cause I miss you, Gary
小蜗  求你回家吧
小蜗回家吧
Gary, come home
小蜗你可曾知
Gary, can't you see
茶店
是我太迟钝
I was blind
愿付出一切
I'll do anything
电器
让你心意改
to change your mind
小蜗
Gary
小蜗回家吧
相簿
不单是宠物  还是朋友
More than a pet, you're my best friend
美妙难忘
too cool to forget
回来吧  我们是一家人
come back 'cause we are family
原谅我从前害你离家去流浪
and forgive me for making you wanna roam
我现在的心正跳着那最悲伤的节拍
And now my heart is beating like the saddest metronome
希望你正在某处
Somewhere I hope you're reading
念着我刚写的短诗
my latest three-word poem
小蜗
回家吧
小蜗  回家吧
Gary, come home
我想要花生
I want peanuts
派大星  不要
Pat, no
丽莎
嫁给我好吗
小蜗  回家吧
Gary, come home
这个丽莎到底是谁
Who is this 'Lisa' person?
什么
What?
老奶奶要从烤箱那拿肉糕给你吃
Gramma will get a lovely meat loaf in the oven for you
放心好了  不麻烦的
Don't worry, it's no trouble at all
小菜一碟
Easy to do
肥肥小妹  你要拉粑粑吗
Miss Tuffsy, do you have to go potty?
要不就拉在这一大叠传单上面吧
Here, why don't you use this stack of fliers
全都是今天一个小胖墩给我的
given to me today by a little chubby boy
亲爱的小蜗
我很对不起
求你回到我身边吧
有没有看到小蜗
看到的话就说我爱他
海绵宝宝
小蜗
求你回来吧
我好想你
小蜗你在哪
对不起
小蜗回来吧
小蜗
我是笨蛋
小蜗  求你回到我身边来
Gary, please come back to me
出发吧  小蜗
Go, boy, go
待在那别动
You stay right there
肉糕就快做好了
The meatloaf is almost done
天哪
Oh, dear
肉糕现在还没有准备好
The meatloaf is not quite ready yet
可是老奶奶知道你有多饿  肥肥小妹
but Gramma knows how hungry you are, Miss Tuffsy
所以人家做好了一小盘饼干
so she whipped up a quick batch of cookies
跑
Run
你不想要饼干吗
You don't want cookies?
放心
Don't fret
我还做了一盘恶魔蛋
I made a batch of deviled eggs, too
回来  肥肥小妹
Come back, Miss Tuffsy
不可以浪费这些吃的  对吧
You don't want these to go to waste, do you?
都是我为爱做的
They were a labor of love
放心好了  肥肥小妹
Don't worry, Miss Tuffsy
老奶奶会找到你的
Gramma will find you
你就是不喜欢玉米片的那位
You're the guy that doesn't like nachos
肥肥小妹  我知道你在那后头
Miss Tuffsy, I know you're back there
我都能听到你肚子叫了
I can hear your stomach growling
你在这啊  肥肥小妹
There you are, Miss Tuffsy
谁
Who?
你肯定是饿坏了
You must be starving
都发泄出来吧  兄弟
Just let it out, buddy
这样才对
That's right
我再也哭不出来了  派大星
I can't cry anymore, Patrick
小蜗一走
When Gary left
也一并带走了我的泪水
He took all my tears with him
你刚说到小蜗了吗
Did you just say Gary?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
我记起来了
I just remembered
今天早些时候我在手工店里
Earlier today at the craft store
我看到了
I saw
好大块的木块
these huge chunks of balsa wood
质量可好了
They were awesome
小蜗喜欢木块
Gary loved balsa wood
我得把小蜗忘掉
I got to try to forget Gary
可是不知为何  我就是忘不掉
For some reason, I can't get him out of my mind
你有见到我吗
我搞砸了
I blew it
全都是我的错
I really blew it
我之前没把你当一回事  小蜗
I took you for granted, Gary
我对不起你
I'm sorry
别光这样瞪我  快说句话啊
Don't just stare at me, say something
我在跟广告牌讲话
I'm talking to a billboard
现在还幻听了
Now I'm hearing things
要是我能再见到你一次就好了
If only I could see you one more time
这样我就能再告诉你  我有多爱你
so I could tell you how much I love you
要是能再听到你喵一声就好了
If only I could hear you meow one last time
没错  就像是这样
Yeah, like that
小蜗  你的呼噜声让我更难忘掉你了
Gary, your purring is making it hard to forget you
小蜗
Gary
那你刚刚有没有听到那番话
So, did you hear any of that
我需不需要再重复给你讲一遍
or do I have to repeat myself?
那就好
Okay, good
我保证  小蜗
I promise, Gary
我不会再像之前那样子对你了
Things are going to be different between you and I
等着瞧吧  兄弟
You'll see, pal
回家给你点东西吃
Now let's go home and get you something to eat
你肯定是饿坏了
You must be starving
不知道是哪出了错
I wonder how things went so wrong
我转过身小蜗不见了
I turned around and he was gone
小蜗在哪
Where's Gary?
每晩我向小蜗的空床扪心自问
Each night I ask his empty bed
是我说了错话吗
Was it something that I said?
我脑袋里的小声音
The little voice inside my head
说小蜗去哪了
says "Where has Gary gone?”
小蜗去哪了
Where has Gary gone?
告诉我
Tell me
小蜗去哪了
Where has Gary gone?
小蜗在哪
Where's Gary?
小蜗
Gary?